Absolutely amazing, wow, it's a pity you can't come work with us
but you're always welcome to come for internships or anything like that, everything is open to you
I mentioned in my previous two videos
This time, our Cheetah Mobile hosted an AI hackathon
The most dazzling dark horse was a junior high school student.
He was far ahead the entire afternoon
was only caught up in the final minutes
He came very close to winning the championship. Right after the competition, I
quickly sought his advice
Listening to the whole thing gave me goosebumps
Everyone will understand why I was so shocked after watching it
Why was I so shocked at that time
I heard that during the competition
Were you leading for a long time, so you had a lot of strategies?
Yes
I first
Because there are some small projects
actually don't require my time to intervene
So I first let those small projects, batch create virtual environments for them
let them run on their own
Once they're finished running, just submit them directly.
Most of the morning and afternoon
and energy were concentrated on
the last 160-point project
to create a standalone, lightweight tool for managing chat logs
I kept optimizing the logic of that thing
turning it into something resembling a product
packaged into an executable file that can be launched with one click
With just a few simple words
The first thing he knew was the current state of AI programming
For example, what are the fundamental capabilities, right?
For some simple tasks, they just directly trust the AI
without requiring much of your involvement
This time, before the competition,
I first built a few skills that I thought might be useful.
Because I don't have my own skill library either
So I temporarily made a few myself
including this front-end design
and some strategies that might be useful during the competition
I had AI first develop a set of
a strategy for selecting topics
and then as soon as the questions were posted on the webpage
before the PDF was released
crawl down that question
then let the AI help me make decisions
Then, based on this decision, launch different instances to execute separately
This way, it saves me the trouble of evaluating each question myself
and then the time spent on understanding the questions and conveying them to the AI
So basically I didn't even look at the questions
All I did was let the AI generate the strategy
then analyzing the questions
and then finally submit it. What was the opportunity that got you into programming?
Actually, I was exposed to programming at a very young age, and the opportunity probably came from
Probably in a certain book
saw a case about how technology can change lives
and then became very interested in this kind of magical thing
At the beginning, I taught myself.
Later, my parents noticed my interest in this.
basic case usage and the like
which is like the most basic skill in the current AI era
your most basic skills were introduced
After AI programming
What projects have you done? The one you just mentioned that got over 100 stars?
all left
using local models to perform Deepseek and
some previous small models for lightweight
It allows batch summarization
batch modification, and functions like distillation
When developing it, I prioritized security considerations
is purely locally run
I tested it even with just a CPU
it can actually handle it
Because I used a very small distilled model
Wow, this is really great
Look at this, it's really amazing.
It's the dawn of a new era.
His social identity is that of a middle school student
But in the field of AI, he is absolutely a master. These new skills are things
I haven't even had time to learn it yet
he has already started using it
and directly applied it to specific strategies
In today's competition, he managed to stay in first place the whole time
Although he came in second place, it was just by a narrow margin.
This is no coincidence
Actually, using AI effectively
It is a transformation of the mindset system
And there are many new techniques involved in using the tool itself.
What you just said is quite impressive
Truly amazing
Oh, what a pity you can't come work for us, haha
but you're always welcome to come for internships or anything like that
You're welcome to come and exchange ideas, right
We can provide such an atmosphere
including we are also working on robotics-related stuff
If you're interested
You're also welcome to join in more often
It's all open to you
all open to you
The AI-native young generation is indeed different
Later, some of our colleagues communicated with him
It's said that he's even easier to communicate with than our R&D staff
How about it
Are you also amazed by this 14-year-old middle school student?
Welcome to discuss in the comment section